[Music]
[音乐]
at its very simplest Tomcat is a web
最简单的Tomcat是Web服务器，可以在此基础上进行一点扩展
server to expand on that a little bit
there are a series of Java
有一系列Java规范定义了一种
specifications that define a way that
web applications can be written and
可以编写Web应用程序，而Tomcat实现这些规范
Tomcat implements those specifications
and it's one of a number of servers that
它是众多服务器的其中之一，因此Web应用程序开发人员可以
do so a web application developer can
write their web application using the
使用标准API编写其Web应用程序，然后就可以在
standard API and then it can run on
Tomcat it can run on jetty it can run on
Tomcat，可以在Jetty上运行，可以在WebSphere上运行，可以在WebLogic和
WebSphere it can run on WebLogic and
because it's the same interface the same
因为在任何地方都可以移动相同的界面和相同的标准
standard everywhere you can move your
application from one to the other and it
从一个应用程序到另一个应用程序，它将可以正常工作，但是最简单
will just work but at its simplest
Tomcat is a way of running websites is
Tomcat是一种运行网站的方法，与Apache Web完全分开
completely separate from the Apache web
server however if you wish you can get
服务器，但是，如果您希望，您可以使两者进行某种合作
the two to sort of working cooperation
so one of the things that Tomcat doesn't
因此，Tomcat本身内部不做的一件事就是负载概念
do within itself is the idea of load
balancing so if you've got more load
进行平衡，因此如果您的负载超过一台物理服务器无法处理的负载
than one physical server can't handle
and you need to spread it between
您需要将其分散在多个对象之间
multiple ones you need something to
spread that load what we often see
分散负载我们经常看到人们正在做的事情就是将Apache网站
people doing is putting Apache web
server in front of it because it can do
服务器在它前面，因为它可以进行负载平衡，然后坐在
the load balancing and then it sits in
front of Tomcat and it spreads the load
Tomcat的前端，它将负载分散到不同的Tomcat实例之间
between the different Tomcat instances
and then brings the responses back
然后将响应汇总在一起，然后发送给用户
together and sends them off to the users
and we have quite close cooperation
而且我们在Tomcat项目的各个部分和
between bits of the Tomcat project and
bits of the Apache web server project
Apache Web服务器项目的一部分，因为我们有效地拥有了自己的
because we have effectively our own
protocol that we use to do some of that
我们用来进行某些通信的协议，因此我们共同致力于新的
communication so we work together on new
features developing that integration of
开发整合功能的功能我专注于您的特定功能
that I am focused on your particular
projects so I am currently a committer
项目，因此我目前是PMC的提交者和比索的成员
PMC member and a member of the peso
software foundation I have been that for
我从事软件工作很长一段时间，一直致力于
a long time I've been a committer for
the camel product for yeah as I said
我说过的骆驼产品大约是12年，我目前的角色是
about 12 years my current role is as a
professional open source developer I'm
我受雇于red的专业开源开发人员
employed by red
and redhead uses camel in in the middle
和红发在我们的产品中间使用骆驼，所以我目前
of our products so I am currently
heavily involved with camel their camel
大量参与骆驼活动的骆驼基本上是用于整合
is basically used for integration is to
switch I mean I for integration
开关我的意思是说，我参加了集成高科技大会吗？
hi-c algunas ation do they have so many
different IT systems and they need to be
不同的IT系统，它们需要集成在一起，您需要知道数据
integrated connected you know it data
need to be transfer from different
需要从不同的系统转移，其中有很多，所以有很多
system many of them so there are so many
different protocols languages and IT
不同的协议语言，IT系统和操作系统以及
systems and operating systems and
whatnot and data formats and camel is
whatnot和数据格式以及骆驼有点像介于两者之间的胶水
sort of like the glue that sits between
and you can easily more easily integrate
您可以更轻松地集成它们，我从更多系统开始
them I started with more system
integration so more project related to
集成，因此有更多与应用程序运行时相关的项目，因此可以运行一些
application runtimes so running some
stuff and application easily for you and
东西和应用程序很容易为您提供许多功能，您可以
providing a lot of features you can
leverage so I started with this kind of
杠杆，所以我从Apache这样的项目开始，现在我仍在从事
project Apache now I'm still working on
this project still very happy and and
这个项目仍然很开心，是的，这仍然是我的项目，但是我
and yeah it's still my project but I
like a lot I'm also working on big data
像很多人一样，我也在开发与大数据相关的产品，像Apache这样的大数据
related products so big data like Apache
carbon data for instances is a database
碳数据实例是为大数据设计的数据库，我真的很高兴
designed for big data I'm really happy
about this product because it's one of
关于这个产品，因为这是我做过的第一个项目
the first project that I did with
Chinese guys and it was really great
中国人，我正在研究的大数据真的很棒
around big data I'm also working on
Apache beam which is a very key project
Apache Beam是一个非常关键的项目，提供了针对以下语言的API
providing an API for a language that
allows you to design some big data
允许您设计一些大数据管道或分布式处理
pipelines or distributed processing of
data so this project historically on
数据，因此该项目历来在哪个项目上进行
which are working on another project
which is nama Apache you know me is more
那是纳玛·阿帕奇，你知道我更多关于用户配置文件，gdpr之类的东西
about user profiling and gdpr and stuff
like that and the thing that I really
这样，我真正喜欢的东西之间存在某种联系
like is there some connection between
all these products the connection is
所有这些产品的连接是一些项目用户之间的联系
between some project user others for
example you know me is based on Apache
例如，您知道我基于Apache Cara，而Apache Cara是我所负责的项目之一
Cara which is one of project arm I'm
working on for a long time beam using
使用扫射和火花对光束进行长时间工作，因此有很多
fling and spark so there are a lot of
connection between the products it's
产品之间的联系是我所喜欢的东西
what I like you I've been involved with
a few projects but I think the ones I've
一些项目，但我认为这些项目是我通过千斤顶Apache演变而来的
been evolved over a jackrabbit Apache
Jackrabbit and Apache you know me so
Jackrabbit和Apache，您知道我，所以我知道Jackrabbit是很多基础
Jackrabbit I know is foundation of a lot
of different they say content management
他们说内容管理系统不同，所以您拥有像我这样的公司
systems so you have companies like my
own jaya adobe magnolia that are all
自己的jaya adobe玉兰，都以此为基础
using this as the infrastructure for
building content management systems for
为您了解我的Apache构建内容管理系统
apache you know me
we started this really as a project for
我们开始这个项目实际上是为了满足我们自己的需求，所以我们的需求很简单
our own needs so our needs were simple
at first it was just to be able to
起初只是为了能够实时收集
collect in real time the the behavior of
people using our CMS and so that was
人们使用我们的CMS，这就是最初的用例
sort of the initial use case what was
really fascinating was to see that once
真正令人着迷的是，一旦这个项目进入了Apache内部
this project was inside the Apache
foundation people found new uses for it
基金会的人们发现了它的新用途，其中最令人惊讶的是
and one of the most surprising one was a
project we just learned about a few
我们几个月前才刚刚了解的项目，
months ago and it's somebody that built
an integration with slack and SMS
与Slack和SMS系统集成，它们将使用Apache
systems and they would use Apache you
know me as sort of the orchestrating
知道我是这两个外部系统之间的协调系统
system between those two external
systems and this was all done to manage
系统，这基本上是为了管理医疗保健而试图遵循的
healthcare basically trying to follow
people that are suffering from
上瘾的人，只是为了确保
addictions and just to make sure that
you're actually using the system to make
您实际上是在使用系统来确保他们不会迷路，我的意思是
sure that they don't get lost I mean
they don't they'll get forgotten in a
他们不是，他们会以某种方式被遗忘，所以这确实是相当
way and so that's really something quite
incredible because you design a system
令人难以置信，因为您针对特定用例设计了系统，然后
for a specific use case and then
suddenly somebody surprises you with
突然有人用一个完全不同的东西给你一个惊喜
with a completely different one and
that's that's what I love about Apache
那就是我对Apache项目ofb的热爱，本质上就是这样开放
projects ofb is essentially this open
source ERP application development
源ERP应用程序开发框架，可能会有点
framework and it can be a little bit
intimidating it has a broad scope of
恐吓它具有广泛的功能范围，并且是其中之一
functionality and and it's one of those
cases where if you're not careful people
如果您不小心的话，人们会问您哦，f是做什么的，您说
ask you what does oh f is do and you say
oh it does everything
哦，它做了所有的事情，但这不是最好的答案
but that's not the best answer
surprisingly what we do is take of' is
令人惊讶的是，我们要做的是'，然后我们将其成形并形成满足
and then we shape it and form it to meet
the specific needs of our clients so
客户的特定需求，因此最终我们从事的业务是
ultimately we are in the business of
executing strategies right
执行策略吧，我们希望业务人员能够
we like the business person to be able
to set the strategy and then we have a
制定策略，然后获得技术策略支持，因此我们希望
technology strategy support so we want
to understand that business strategy
要非常了解业务战略，我们希望相信
really well we want to believe in it if
we're going to commit to the project we
我们将致力于该项目我们希望您成功，然后我们将
want you to be successful and then we'll
take off this and we'll shape it and
脱掉它，我们将对其进行整形，自定义，扩展和配置
customize it and extend it and configure
it and adjust it to make this bespoke
并对其进行调整以为我们的客户提供此定制解决方案
solution for our client that does
exactly what this business strategy
正是这个商业策略所决定的，我认为这是一件伟大的事情
dictates I think one of the great things
about RDF and even I did not realize
关于RDF，甚至我在深入了解这一点之前都没有意识到
before getting too much into this is
that you can express anything in this
您可以用这种格式表达任何内容，所以我认为这确实导致了
format so I think that really leads to a
lot of applications or possible
大量应用程序或此数据的可能应用程序，因此您可以
applications for this data so you can
say the sky is blue or you can say Edina
说天空是蓝色，或者您可以说Edina是副教授，但您可以
is an associate professor but you can
also say stored data that is financial
还说存储数据是财务数据或只是文档，并说这
data or just documents and say this
document was modified at a particular
文档在特定日期被修改，您可以在这些日期的基础上进行构建
date and you can build on top of these
applications for example that keep track
例如跟踪数据来源的应用程序之一
of data provenance one of the
applications of RIA in the Navy is
RIA在海军中的应用是具有人工智能的无人机
drones with intelligence artificial
intelligence and image recognition so
智能和图像识别，因此您可以让这些无人机飞翔
you can have these drones that fly
around and they can try to do image
他们可以尝试进行图像识别，例如，这是一个
recognition for example this was a
reconnaissance and target acquirement so
侦察和目标获取，所以他们试图在这个领域认识人
they tried to recognize people in this
case of course they ran image
他们当然使用了图像识别算法，并尝试
recognition algorithms and they try to
find a particular person or a particular
找到一个特定的人或一个特定的建筑目标或其他
target for building or whatever the
target is and then you can communicate
目标是，然后您可以与可以进行通信的无人机进行通信
with the drones that you can communicate
with other computers which are on ships
与船上的其他计算机或
or
or down on the ground and they can
或在地面上，他们可以协调整个行动，
coordinate an entire action and
somewhere below all the artificial
在所有人工
intelligence and all the communication a
在所有人工智能和所有通信下面的某个地方
lot of data was actually stored in dia
实际上，很多数据都存储在dia中，因此
so because of this flexibility of the
data format you really can store a lot
数据格式，您真的可以存储很多数据，很多不同类型的数据
of data a lot of different types of data
india and what we are trying it's tree
印度，而我们尝试使用的是可扩展的树，因此您可以存储
is very scalable so you can store
billions of triples and you can ask
数十亿的三元组，您可以在几毫秒内查询
queries in seconds milliseconds and that
really helps in some of these
在某些应用程序中确实有帮助，云堆栈是
applications cloud stack is an
infrastructure as a service platform and
基础架构即服务平台，真正的意思是它
what that really means is that it
abstract away
消除提供服务的所有复杂性
all of the complexities of offering a
infrastructure platform and essentially
基础架构平台，实际上，它是通过提供API和
it does that by by providing an API and
a user interface for a number of very
一个用于许多非常复杂动作的用户界面，
complex actions and makes that very
simple to use and consume cloud stack is
易于使用和使用的云堆栈本​​质上是一种软件，可让您
essentially software that allows you to
have individuals in your organization
让您组织中的个人根据一组资源
provision resources according to a set
of rules and those could be business
规则，这些可以是业务规则或技术规则，并允许它们
rules or technical rules and allow them
to get things done in a in a fast manner
快速完成工作，因为他们从本质上说
because they've they've essentially been
delegated some technical and
委派了一些技术和组织权限来进行操作
organizational authority to get things
done now this provides essentially a
现在完成的操作基本上提供了一个技术层，使人们能够
technical layer that allows people to
action things so you can have an
采取行动，这样您就可以拥有需要测试的个人开发人员
individual developer who needs a test
environment for testing software and
测试软件的环境，而不是要求人们站起来
rather than asking people to stand up a
test environment for him he would make
他的测试环境，他将进行API调用或登录用户
an API call or he would log into a user
interface and stand up that test
界面并自己站起来测试环境，因此云堆栈是
environment himself so cloud stack is
really about providing access to a set
真正涉及提供对一组组织资源的访问并让
of organizational resources and letting
you actually get work accomplished but
您实际上可以完成工作，却不必强迫所有复杂的工作
without forcing all of the complexity of
having to know about how to provision so
必须知道如何配置，从而消除了一些复杂性，
remove some of that complexity and
allows you to focus on getting the
让您专注于完成基础工作
underlying work accomplished that you
need to do I got involved with Tomcat
我需要做的事涉及Tomcat大约15
about 15
years ago I was working as an IT
多年前，我担任IT顾问，我们正在做一些工作
consultant and we were doing some work
with SSL authentication and the product
使用SSL身份验证，我们使用的产品无法正常工作
we were using wasn't working properly so
he switched to JBoss which at that time
他改用了当时嵌入了tomcat的JBoss，我们得到了一个
had tomcat embedded in it and we got a
lot further with it there's one little
更进一步的是，它没有做一件事，因为它是
thing it didn't do so because it was
open-source I was able to look at the
开源我能够查看源代码并找到注释
source code and find the comment that
said to do must make this configurable
据说要做的事必须使这种可配置的思想更加出色，我可以做到
thought brilliant I can do that
submitted a patch had that patch pretty
提交了一个补丁，该补丁几乎被撕裂了，非常好，但是它
much torn apart and very nicely but it
was torn apart showing all the ways I
被撕裂了，显示了我应该做得更好的所有方式，所以我采取了
should have done it better so I took
that advice improved the patch submitted
该建议改进了修补程序，再次提交了该修补程序，使其成为Tomcat的一部分
it again and it became part of Tomcat
and I found it something I really
我发现它是我真正喜欢的东西，并且是对此进行研究的一部分
enjoyed and as part of researching that
I'd realized that all there's all these
我意识到所有其他数百个需要修复的错误
other hundreds of bugs that need fixing
as well perhaps I'll do some of those so
也许我会做一些这样的事情，所以我以这种方式开始参与
I got involved that way started fixing
bugs and it have essentially been doing
自从我认为那件事以来，它就一直在这样做
that ever since I think that the thing
that I get most satisfaction from is
我最满意的是当我开始参与
when I started my involvement in the
Tomcat project we had something like 600
在Tomcat项目中，这些天来，当我们执行
plus open bugs these days when we do a
release we have zero essentially we've
发布，我们基本上是零，我们有一些开放的增强功能，但是
got a few open enhancement requests but
the actual bugs they're fixed so
他们已修复的实际错误，因此可以通过该列表
actually working through that list of
open bugs and reviewing them and closing
打开错误并进行检查并正确关闭它们
them properly not sort of there
oh well it's been open for a year so
哦，它已经开放了一年，所以我们将其关闭，因为没有人
we'll just close it because nobody's
looking at it anymore
看着它实际上正在审查它审查
actually reviewing it examining it
working it with it's really a bug if it
如果不能解决原因，则对其进行修复确实是一个错误。
is fixing it if it's not explaining why
and closing it legitimately I think
并合法地关闭它，我认为将错误列表降为零
getting the bug list down to zero for
tomcat is something that I'm
tomcat让我感到特别高兴的是
particularly pleased that I had a big
part in what often surprises me is all
经常让我感到惊讶的部分是Tomcats所使用的所有地方，而我从未
the places that Tomcats use that I never
knew about I was at a conference and
知道我在开会，有人在谈论网络
somebody was giving a talk about web
application performance and shooting so
应用程序的性能和拍摄，因此可能很有趣的是
all that could be quite interesting is
it's an area that technically I like to
从技术上讲，这是我喜欢听的地方，所以我进入了
hear about and so I went onto the
presentation and discovered that
演示并发现NFL在美国的所有网站都是
NFL in the US all their websites were
based on Tomcat whether that still the
基于Tomcat是否仍然不知道这种情况，但那时候是
case I don't know but back then it was
eBay uses a lot of Tomcat and I didn't
eBay使用了很多Tomcat，但直到eBay出现并说
know that until eBay turned up and said
but yeah we losing using a lot of Tomcat
但是，是的，我们损失了很多Tomcat，并且获得了相当多的网页浏览量
and we get quite a few pageviews you
might have heard of us and these few
可能听说过我们以及这几个地方
places where it's not quite as quick as
it could be here are some changes we've
这可能是我们所做的一些更改，您是否可以帮助我们将其放入
made could you help us put them into the
codes yeah absolutely and we worked with
是的，绝对可以，我们与他们合作来整合他们的补丁，因此
them to incorporate their patches so
what I find is that lots and lots of
我发现的是，那里有很多公司在使用
companies that are there are using
Tomcat taking advantage of it and doing
Tomcat可以利用它并做各种事情，无论它们是否
all sorts of things whether they be
commercial entities whether they be
商业实体，无论他们是否是教育机构，
educational institutes the fact that
it's it's there it's available and
它在那里，人们可以利用它，我认为是
people can make use of it I think is
great
我很棒，很高兴看到
I sort of was very happy to see sort of
the public interest with all this
所有行业4.0数字化和生产的公共利益
industry 4.0 digitization and production
industry sort of coming up because it
行业之所以出现，是因为这全都与Apache的软件有关
was all about software Apache for
example had to offer it was sort of like
示例必须提供的有点像大数据机器学习云
Big Data machine learning cloud
technology and all the stuff we have so
技术和我们拥有的所有东西，所以我真的很期待
I was really looking forward to doing
industrial IOT projects because I have
工业物联网项目，因为我不得不承认我不是那种云计算专家
to admit I'm not that sort of cloud guy
I really like physical things so it's
我真的很喜欢物理事物，所以对我来说，进行控制会更有趣
for me it's more fun to sort of control
some huge engines and robots so I was
一些巨大的引擎和机器人，所以我真的很期待，但是
really looking forward to that but it
wasn't happening because so if I did a
不会发生，因为如果我做了一点研究为什么会这样
little research why that was the case
and I finally found out it's the main
我终于发现，主要的问题是我们无法交谈
problem was that we weren't able to talk
to the industrial hardware because they
到工业硬件，因为它们使用的是完全不同的
were using completely different
technologies completely different
技术完全不同的协议，所以我目前的主要重点是
protocols so my current main focus is a
project I was happy to initiate it's
我很高兴启动一个名为Apache PLC 4x的项目，这就是我们
called Apache PLC 4x so this is our
little mascot and what we're trying to
小吉祥物，我们正在尝试做的是，我们正在尝试建立一种
do is we're trying to build sort of a
universal library for communicating with
通用库，用于与它们使用的工业硬件进行通信
industrial hardware they sort of use
protocols to exchange information
信息交换协议，这些协议通常非常
and these protocols are usually very
highly proprietary and so a device from
高度专有，因此制造商的设备通常可以与
manufacturer a can usually just talk to
the devices of manufacturer a so
制造商的设备导致供应商锁定
resulting in sort of a vendor lock-in
and what we're doing is sort of where
我们正在做的是有时在哪里实施这些协议的地方
sometimes implementing those protocols
by reading the spec or by implementing
通过阅读规范或有时通过反向实施规范
the spec sometimes by reverse
engineering the protocols and hereby
对协议进行工程​​设计，因此可以
were sort of yeah making it possible to
communicate the same way with any
与我们通常使用的任何工业硬件进行相同的通信
industrial hardware we usually use the
term industrial IOT or a IOT as we do
术语“工业物联网”或“物联网”，因为我们不像小工具或
not work with like small gadgets or our
smartwatches and mobile phones or
智能手表和手机，或其他通常与我们合作的产品
whatever but we usually work with
machines big machines as we I personally
机器大机器，因为我个人来自德国南部
come from the south of Germany we have a
lot of machine manufacturers there and
那里有很多机器制造商，所有这些机器都有控制器
all of those machines have controllers
software's controllers are twenty or
该软件的控制器已有20或30年的历史
thirty years old
because they're meant to be robust and
因为它们本来就很健壮并且可以工作，而且它们是相当复杂的部分
work and they are rather complex pieces
of hardware but not optimized for
硬件，但未针对互操作性进行优化，而是要使其健壮
interoperability but rather to be robust
and and provide real-time capabilities
并提供实时功能安全功能来控制那些
safety functions to control those big
machines and those machines can really
机器，这些机器真的可以重达五十吨甚至更多，并且
weight fifty tons or even more and be
several meters long and high basically
几米长高基本上永远之间
forever there has been the gap between
the Machine infrastructure or the
机器基础架构或与机器的网络进行通信
network with machines communicate with
each other and the IT landscape so
彼此之间以及IT领域，因此通常我们在
usually we have different networks in
those factories now with all the
这些工厂现在具备我们必须存储数据到的所有功能
capabilities we have to store data to
analyze data to extract information
分析数据以提取人们想要使用我们已知工具的信息
people want to use the tools we know
from the big data area from the aia
来自aia研究的常规应用中的大数据领域
research from regular application
development and want to apply those
开发并希望将这些技术应用于机器或数据
techniques to the machines or to data
gathered from those machines many of
从这些机器中收集了许多您可以用来说话的协议
those protocols you you can use to speak
to the machines are proprietary
机器是专有的老式
old-fashioned
and what we tried to do if the POC Forex
以及如果POC外汇项目基本上是在此之间架起了桥梁
project is basically bridge this
language barrier so we want to provide
语言障碍，所以我们想为每个人提供驾驶机会
drivers possibilities for everybody in
IT to speak to those machines and those
IT与那些机器和那些控制器对话，以便我们基本上可以开放
controllers so that we basically open up
the door to use the regular IT landscape
使用常规IT环境与机器和计算机一起工作的大门
to work together with machines and
production sites for example we have
例如生产现场，我们在铸造领域有客户，但有
customers in the foundry area but have
big machines that that produce sand
产生沙粒的大型机器
coarse
so basically sand is compressed to build
因此基本上将沙子压缩以构建核心，然后将其用于创建
the core which is then used to create a
hole in a casting and the process is
铸件中的孔，过程非常复杂，有化学物质
quite complex there are chemical
processes involved in physical processes
涉及到物理过程的过程，直到现在
involved and up till now it's some kind
of modern alchemy because nobody knows
炼金术的概念，因为没有人确切地知道在
exactly how everything works together at
which parameter to adjust when and my
何时和我使用POC Forex调整哪个参数能够提取所有
using POC Forex were able to extract all
those parameters related to the quality
这些参数与最终产品的质量有关，并且非常接近
of the end product and and really close
the feedback loop to get a better
反馈循环以更好地了解哪个兄弟
understanding of which bros has
influenced the product one thing I
我对产品产生了影响我注意到的一件事是，很多人
noticed was that a lot of people have
been building database management
一直在建立数据库管理系统，我使用类似的类比
systems and I use the analogy it's kind
of like climbing a mountain that if you
就像爬山一样，如果您是登山者，
if you're a mountaineer the the first
part of the journey is always the same
旅程的一部分总是一样的，这很无聊，因为你
and it's pretty boring because you're
just walking up through trees and so
穿过树木等等，就必须走到10,000英尺
forth and you have to get to 10,000 feet
before the snow starts and so building
在大雪开始之前，所以建立数据库管理系统只是
database management system just kind of
like that you have to do a lot of basic
这样，您每次构建一个建筑时都必须做很多基本的事情，
stuff every time you build one and
there's a lot of people in Silicon
硅谷和世界各地都有很多人
Valley and around the world building
database management systems and all
数据库管理系统和所有系统都做同样的事情，因此该项目
doing the same stuff so the project that
I'm working on Apache calcite is an
我正在研究Apache方解石是一种跳过无聊的尝试
attempt to kind of skip over the boring
bits of the mountain and get into the
进入山峰，进入有趣的地方，我注意到
interesting area I noticed that when
people build
人们建立一个数据库，他们做很多相同的事情
a database they do a lot of the same
stuff and what I wanted to do is
东西，我想做的是消除一些常见的苦恼
eliminate some of that common drudgery
by building a toolkit a framework for
通过构建工具箱和用于构建数据库管理系统的框架
building a database management system
and so Apache calcite is that we took
因此，Apache方解石是我们采用了关系数据库的核心部分
the core parts of a relational database
such as the parser and the query
例如解析器和查询优化器
optimizer
and repackaged it in a way that people
并以人们可以将其用作构建他们的工具包的方式重新包装它
could use it as a toolkit to build their
own database and the result of that has
自己的数据库，其结果是，这是一次协作
been that it's been a a collaboration
across many companies and many
许多公司和个人都在努力
individuals each of whom is trying to
build a data management system or a
建立数据管理系统或数据库管理系统，以便我们拥有
database management system so we have a
lot of collaborators from different
来自不同公司的许多合作者，每个人都有相似之处
companies each of whom have similar
requirements that but not exactly the
但并不完全相同的要求，所以当我使用Apache时
same and so when I'm working on Apache
calcite I'm working with peers who have
方解石我正在与与我有相同目标的同龄人一起工作
the same goals as I do they might be in
companies that are competing with my
与我的公司竞争的公司，但在这里我们可以
company but it's a place that we can
share work we can talk directly to each
分享工作，我们可以直接彼此交谈，而不必经过您
other rather than having to go via you
know the companies go via managers or
知道公司通过经理或违反公司法律部门
violate company's legal departments it's
a direct communication with my peers and
与我的同龄人进行直接交流，他们发现很容易对他们进行评分和
they find that very easily rating and
very productive so calcite has
高产，方解石滚雪球，因为它已经变成
snowballed you know as it has become
more stable and more fully featured and
更稳定，功能更全，其声誉不断提高，我们发现了更多
its reputation has grown we find more
and more companies and projects just
和更多的公司和项目一样，几乎像默认选项一样使用它
using it almost like the default option
if you're going to build a database
如果要建立数据库，请使用Apache calcite启动
start up with Apache calcite you're
crazy to build a sequel parser why don't
疯狂地制作续集解析器为什么不使用方解石稀疏
you use calcite sparsa that kind of
stuff and we hear that more and more you
的东西，我们听到越来越多的你知道这是花了很长时间
know it's it's taken a long time to
become an overnight success I mean it's
成为一夜之间的成功我的意思是这花了七年时间，但我们只是听说
taken seven years but we just hear it's
actually really nice to hear of a
真的很高兴听到数据库进入市场，然后
database hitting the market and then
finding out that it has calcite inside
发现里面有方解石，我们甚至不知道那是
and we're not even aware of it that's
one of the wonderful things and and
关于开源的奇妙和令人沮丧的事情之一是
frustrating things about open source is
that people might be using your software
人们可能正在使用您的软件，而您甚至不知道它，直到
and you don't even know about it until
they hit a bug and then they have an
他们遇到了一个bug，然后就有动力去参与
incentive to get involved in the
community and try and you know figure
社区并尝试，您会知道解决该错误的方法，因此我们有两个
out how to solve that bug so we have two
major projects in Apache foundation
Apache Foundation中的主要项目现在都是顶级项目之一
right now both are top tier projects one
is called double which is an RPC
被称为double，这是一个RPC框架，另一个称为
framework and the other one is called
rocky MQ is it's a enterprise level
洛基MQ是企业级企业级消息q两者都非常
enterprise grade message q both are very
successful in China before we donated
在将它们捐赠给Apache基金会之前在中国取得了成功，但是
them to Apache foundation but the good
thing about putting them under a prodigy
现在把他们放在神童的基础上
foundation is now we have collaboration
from the community so now the bows have
来自社区，所以现在的弓箭不仅已经成为事实
become not only de-facto
when people are looking for our PC
当人们在寻找我们的PC框架或消息队列时，
frameworks or message queues but also
they are actually becoming the projects
他们实际上正在成为社区中的项目，例如岩石MQ
from the community for example rocky MQ
we have we have PMC members from five
我们有来自五家不同公司的PMC成员，其中12家中的12家
different companies and 12 of 12 of them
so Alibaba is no longer in country of
因此，阿里巴巴不再在该项目的国家/地区，但我们很乐意
that project anymore but we'd love to
see it we see new features we never
看到它，我们看到阿里巴巴内部从未想到的新功能
thought of inside of Alibaba that's
being developed being proposed being
正在开发中正在提议在社区中开发
developed in the community for example
we were a heavy-duty
我们是一家重型Java商店，我们从不想要任何SDK
Java shop we never wanted any SDKs in
other languages but since we donated
其他语言，但由于我们捐赠了该项目并从Apache毕业
this project and graduated from Apache
incubation now we have SDKs in c plus
孵化现在我们在c plus中有SDK，在其他Golan Internet中也有
plus in Golan Internet in other
languages as well so it has absolutely
语言，因此它绝对活跃，因为社区拥有
being active because the community has
driven that way and the same thing was
以这种方式开车，同一件事是双重的，所以以前有很多人
double so there are so many folks before
that people were using it taking in
人们正在使用它，深入了解他们将如何适应或使用
depth of how they will adapt or use
double inside of their own companies
在自己的公司内部加倍，但现在我们已经
but now we've
nice umbrella people actually come and
好的伞人实际上是来把他们的想法带到社区的，
bring their ideas to the community and
making double more modern or clown
在这个世界上使现代人或小丑本地人倍增，这就是
native in this world so that's that's
the value that Apache foundation has
Apache基金会为佛罗里达番石榴带来的价值以及
added to us of Florida guava and for the
community as well
社区以及整个中国，所以社区真的
overall in China so the community really
flourished with in OpenOffice
在OpenOffice中蓬勃发展，它是一种全球性的分布式
and it was a global kind of distributed
community that we built over time for an
我们随着时间的推移为社区办公套件而建立的社区
office productivity suite that was
pretty popular in its time you know
您知道它在当时很受欢迎
available on multiple platforms of
course now we have a patty OpenOffice so
当然，现在我们有了一个小巧的OpenOffice，这就是apache的历史
that was some of the history of apache
openoffice is very steeped in the apache
由于我们的指导，openoffice在apache方式中非常浸泡
way because of the mentorship that we
had from apache founders and the apache
来自apache创始人和apache社区的下一个项目
community the next project that I was
involved in was NetBeans the Java IDE
参与的是NetBeans Java IDE，我参与了构建
and I got involved in building
governance model that really included
真正包含社区以及NetBeans的治理模型
the community as well and there NetBeans
had been acquired by sun at that time
当时是被太阳吸收的，并且在
and and there were some tensions in
terms of you know how the you know
您知道您对公司控制与社区控制的了解
company control versus the community's
original way of working so we found a
原始的工作方式，因此我们找到了一种适用于社区的模型，
model that worked for the community and
for son as well and you know it's really
对于儿子来说，也很高兴看到NetBeans也是
great to see that NetBeans is also an
Apache project so we can see that you
Apache项目，因此我们可以看到您了解我的早期经历
know my kind of early days of
open-source work very connected to
开源工作与Apache紧密相连，而不仅仅是社区
Apache and the not just the community
but also it's great to see those
但也很高兴看到这些项目现在可以在Apache
projects now and living on in Apache the
first patch that I submitted was early
我提交的第一个补丁是2003年初的Apache ant项目
2003 that was to the Apache ant project
we were had written some testing tools
我们已经在
using building upon on top of the the
ant framework and we needed some
ant框架，我们需要进行一些增强以使ant成为
enhancements to actually make ant be
able to read databases better
能够更好地读取数据库，这就是我参与提交的方式
so that's how I got involved submitted
some patches got some feedback even
即使我们使用的是带有XML的补丁，有些补丁也得到了一些反馈
though we're using an - which had an XML
flavored syntax to it we for our testing
为了我们的测试目的，我们需要更多的语法
purposes we needed a little bit more
scripting capability and so I actually
脚本功能，所以我实际上开始使用groovy语言
started using the groovy language to
script the the ant steps that we were
编写脚本，这些脚本是我们多年来用于测试的步骤
using for our testing and many years
later it came full circle when we moved
后来，当我们
Apache groovy into Apache when we were
previously hosted at code house and that
以前托管在代码所，现在已关闭，我们将
was shutting down and we moved the
groovy project to Apache I worked for a
Apache的groovy项目我曾在很多公司工作，最近我已经
bunch of companies and lately I've
worked at Google for five years and we
在Google工作了五年，我们在Google Cloud数据流中工作
I've worked on Google Cloud dataflow
it's it's a big data processing system
这是一个大数据处理系统，并且它的客户端始终是开放的
and the client for it was always an open
source sdk and we some other people
来源sdk，我们还有其他人将其拾起并为
picked it up and made translators for
apache flink and apache spark and at
apache flink和apache spark，那时Google决定合作
that point Google decided to collaborate
with them and try to begin Apache beam
和他们一起尝试开始Apache Beam，这就是这种可移植性
which would be this sort of portability
lay layer so you could author your big
外层，以便您可以编写大数据处理并可以在
data processing and you could run it on
a patchy spark or patchy flank or on
斑点状的火花或斑点状的侧面或Google Cloud数据流上的斑点，因此
Google Cloud dataflow and so so that's
how I came I came to Apache really
我是怎么来的我真的是通过这种自上而下的方式来到Apache的
through this really sort of top down
initiative to donate the code to the
主动将代码捐赠给Apache并开始孵化
Apache and start incubating so at a
jewelry television
珠宝电视如此幽默，你知道这些
so humorously enough you know these
types of you know analysis platforms or
您知道分析平台或工具集的类型
you know tool sets they're almost
unheard of in the physics community so
在物理学界是闻所未闻的，所以一旦我搬到电视，你就知道我们开始了
once I moved to jtv you know we started
working on our Big Data Platform and big
在我们的大数据平台和大数据堆栈上工作，然后您就知道了
data stacks and you know then I've
really started to learn more about you
真正开始了解更多有关您的知识，您知道很多这类工具
know a lot of these types of tools you
know specifically spark and Kafka and
特别了解spark和Kafka之类的东西，现在我就像哦
things like that and now I was like oh
man I really want to learn more about
男人，我真的想了解更多关于这些的知识，因为你知道这些是工具
these because you know these are tools
that can solve a lot of problems and I
可以解决很多问题，我听说您知道，就像是，优步Uber
heard you know it's like oh yeah Uber's
using you know spark and you know
使用您知道的火花，并且您知道linkedin大量使用kafka
linkedin is using kafka for a lot of
their messaging you know and then I
他们知道的消息，然后我猜火箭MQ和所有这类
guess rocket MQ and all that kind of
stuff you know and I was like oh this
你知道的东西，我就像哦，这听起来像很多你知道的工具
sounds like a lot of tools you know it's
like my date
就像我的约会，你知道我们在做什么
you know for a lot of what we're doing
it's like mom will never approach those
就像妈妈永远不会接近这样的尺寸
kind of this kind of sizes it's like
yeah you're trying to manage all
是的，您正在尝试管理所有您知道的推文或消息的Twitter
Twitter's you know tweets or messages
and LinkedIn it's like oh yeah we use
和LinkedIn就像哦，是的，我们用袖扣去做一些我觉得还可以的事情
cuff go to do some of that I'm like okay
cool then we can certainly handle our
很酷，那么我们当然可以处理我们的数据，所以您知道能够
data it's so you know being able to you
know kind of come to the community and
知道进入社区并从社区中学习并与人们和您交谈
learn from it and talk to people and you
know kind of hear what other people are
知道听到别人在做什么Hadoop是一个程序，可以让您
doing Hadoop is a program that lets you
run your program on a lot of different
一次在许多不同的机器上运行您的程序，而部分
machines at once and part of having to
run on lots of machines at once is in
实际上一次在许多机器上运行实际上是在处理故障，因为如果
fact dealing with failures because if
your machine at home breaks every three
您家里的机器每三年发生一次故障，这意味着如果您有一千台
years that means if you have a thousand
machines running there's going to be
每天运行三台机器，我们
three machines breaking each day and we
in practice rolling on clusters of 5,000
实际上是在5,000台计算机的群集上滚动，因此您会有很多
machines and so you'd have lots of
machines breaking every day so you can't
机器每天都在损坏，所以您不需要人类做任何事情
have the humans need to do anything
everything has to be automatic one of my
一切都必须自动完成我在LinkedIn上的一位朋友正在运行
friends at LinkedIn was running the
clusters there and he was trying to
在那里聚集，他试图说服老板，他们没有
convince his bosses that they didn't
need to keep buying expensive hardware
需要继续购买昂贵的硬件，因此他列出了机器清单
and so he pulled up the list of machines
in the meeting and said please pick one
在会议上说，请选一个，他们是否立即将其关闭
and they did he shut it down immediately
with just a halt no warning no graceful
只是停止而没有警告，没有正常关机只是停止而已
shutdown just a halt and that halt
didn't cause any pagers to go off
不会导致任何传呼机退出，无需执行所有
nothing had to be done all the data that
was there was immediately just put onto
马上被从其他机器上放到其他机器上
other machines from the machines that
were still up the work load had already
仍然在工作负荷上已经在其他机器上运行，所以这是
run onto other machines and so that was
automatically handled the failure was
自动处理故障是完全自动处理的，
handled completely automatically and
nothing had to be done manually to keep
无需手动进行任何操作即可使其继续运行
it going
so an example of that kind of program
所以这类程序的一个例子
well the first example that of that kind
of program was building an index of the
的程序正在建立Web的索引，以便执行搜索引擎
web so in order to do a search engine
you really need to have a complete
您确实需要不仅对所有页面都有完整的了解
understanding of not only all the pages
on the web that text they contain but
在网络上包含这些文本，但是它们如何链接在一起，因为
how they all linked together because the
pages that are linked by more pages at
在各个站点上由更多页面链接的页面
various sites
are a better page and the text that
是一个更好的页面，而与他们链接的文本实际上是一个更好的页面
they're linked with actually is a better
description of what's on the page than
对页面内容的描述要比页面本身上的文字描述好
the text on the page itself so you
actually need to analyze the whole web
实际上需要分析整个网络，构建所有不同的地图
build this map of all the different
links and so when we're at Yahoo we had
链接，所以当我们在Yahoo时，我们有一万亿个页面和10万亿个链接
a trillion pages and 10 trillion links
and we'd build a map of that entire
我们将构建整个图运行算法的地图以找出
graph run algorithms over to figure out
which are the best pages what search
哪个页面最好？每个页面上应包含哪些搜索词
terms should be on each page and that
was all done with Hadoop by the time we
在完成工作时，所有工作都已由Hadoop完成，我们可以运行该流程
were done and we could run the process
on I do much more quickly than we could
我的工作速度比以前的系统快得多
do it on the previous system the
previous system had taken a month to run
以前的系统要花一个月的时间才能与Hadoop一起运行，所以我们将其减少到不到
with Hadoop we got it down to less than
a week yes the idea of calcite did
一个星期，方解石的想法确实发生在ASF之外
happen outside of the ASF it was
originally a project called Optique I
最初是一个名为Optique的项目，我有这个主意，实际上我创建了
had the idea and actually I created the
project by actually cutting down so a
通过实际削减项目数量，使我之前拥有过一个开源项目，
previous open-source project I had and
around 2012 this was the peak of the big
在2012年左右，这是大数据运动的顶峰。
data movement Apache Hadoop was very
successful and there was a lot of
成功，创建大数据技术的活动很多
activity in creating big data technology
notably a lot of this was doing similar
值得注意的是，很多工作与数据库做了类似的工作，但是人们
work to databases but the people
building it were at pains to say this
很难说这不是数据库，所以
isn't a database this stuff is so
different we don't need sequel and I
不一样，我们不需要续集，我有点不同意，我可以看到
kind of disagreed with that I could see
that you know Big Data and Hadoop it was
您知道大数据和Hadoop是数据管理，人们将
data management and people were going to
need sequel eventually so it made sense
最终需要续集，所以我以前去过这个项目很有意义
to take this project that I was I'd been
working on as an individual and get how
以个人的身份工作，并了解将其带入
it made sense to bring it into the
Apache Software Foundation so that it
Apache Software Foundation，以便它可以开始发展社区并
could start to grow a community and
start to grow adoption within the other
开始在其他项目和其他公司中被采用，
projects and by the other companies that
were pushing the big data movement so I
推动大数据运动，所以我实际上加入了Hortonworks
actually joined Hortonworks which was
one of them
其中一家支持Hadoop和
companies that was backing Hadoop and
they asked me to carry on working on
他们要求我继续进行方解石的研究，这也有助于我提出疑问
calcite would also help I've put a query
optimizer into hive using calcite and at
与方解石同时使用方解石将优化器配置为蜂巢
the same time as that I was working with
the Apache drill project which was
由map编写的Apache演练项目是
written by map are a major competitor to
Hortonworks so virtually from day one I
Hortonworks几乎从我工作的第一天开始就被一家公司支付给
was working I was paid by one company to
work on technology which was being used
研究该公司主要竞争对手使用的技术，以及
by that company's arch competitor and
everyone was fine with that because
每个人都很好，因为那基本上就是我们的工作方式
that's how it works basically we were
all creating value you know we were
所有创造价值的过程，您都知道我们正在创造，我不会说我们正在创造
making I won't say we were making the
world a better place but we were making
世界是一个更好的地方，但我们正在打造一个非常有趣的功能强大的地方
building a very interesting powerful
technology stack that made it possible
技术栈使我们两家公司都可以发布
for both of our companies to release
really good products for our customers
对于我们的客户而言，真正好的产品不是那种零和游戏
it's not a zero-sum game that's the kind
of the message of open source if I do
如果我做一些使我的产品更好的事情
something that makes my product better
and I happen to make your product better
我碰巧使您的产品更好，那很棒的社区永远是
that's great community was always a
really important thing for us and when
对我们来说非常重要，当代码库关闭时，我们
code house was shutting down we were
looking for a new home for groovy there
在寻找新的时髦住宅，有很多人投资了
was lots of people who've invested in in
the groovy technology by building
通过在其之上构建框架和库来开发常规技术
frameworks and libraries on top of it
and what we really wanted was a place
我们真正想要的是一个所有这些人都可以安全居住的地方
where all of those people could safely
Park groovy and all be contributing and
公园风格，所有人都在贡献力量，社区可以蓬勃发展，而不是没有
a community could thrive and not and no
single vendor could come in and take
单个供应商可以进入并接管该语言并将其定向到
over the language and direct it in a
direction that might impact all the
可能影响常规生态系统中所有其他参与者的方向，因此
other players in the groovy ecosystem so
the ASF was a great place to bring
ASF是带来时髦的好地方，这是社区的精神
groovy and it's the the community ethos
that was in apache mirrored very much
在Apache中，这非常反映了groovy所拥有的社区
the kind of community that groovy had
been fostering outside ASF and that was
一直在ASF之外培养，这对我们以及我们
the big attraction for us and what we
found was a really important part for
发现对于ASF来说确实很重要，因此我们产生了大量数据
the ASF so we produce tons of data
basically by by extracting all those
基本上是从机器中提取所有这些参数，这是
parameters from the machines and this is
exactly the problem
正是物联网数据库解决的问题
IOT DB solves
so this is one project we use to store
所以这是我们现在用来存储这些状态以供以后分析的一个项目
those state now for later analysis to
have it long term available if one sees
如果有人发现几个月有问题，可以长期使用
that there's a problem several months
later you can always go back and look at
以后您可以随时返回查看数据，它们很容易访问
the data and they are easily accessible
but at the same time do not consume much
但是同时不消耗太多内存，所以这是一个难题
memory so this is one puzzle piece
basically ended into the whole picture
基本上结束了整个图景，另一个是数据分析，
and another one is data analysis where
we are several server projects and the
我们是几个服务器项目，而ASF是一个古老的框架
ASF one is acient which is a framework
to build exactly this kind of analytic
来构建这种运行在边缘的分析应用程序，但是我们
applications running at the edge but we
also use other projects like apache
也使用其他项目，例如apache flink，这是众所周知的
flink which is very well known as a
streaming framework or Apache knife IO
流框架或Apache刀IO缩小，这也是一种不错的方法
minify which also is a nice way to
analyze data what we do then in detail
分析数据，然后我们进行详细的分析，专门针对那些
is rather specifically to use cases that
may be very simple questions like how
可能是非常简单的问题，例如机器在
long did the machine operate in a
specific time range but can be more and
特定时间范围，但可能会越来越复杂，例如识别特定时间范围
more complex like recognizing specific
shapes to see for example that the
可以查看例如能耗异常或
energy consumption is abnormal or which
could be related to some kind of failure
可能与某种故障或老化过程有关，
or aging process there's a wide range of
application specific things and what we
特定于应用程序的事情，我们正在尝试做的是帮助填充
are trying to do is to help to populate
the ecosystem in the Apache foundation
Apache基础中的生态系统，以使其易于构建
to make it easy to to build together
this kind of application from several
来自几个构建基块的此类应用程序我是副总裁
building blocks I'm the vice-president
of Apache labs which is an internal
Apache实验室，这是一个内部创新领域，人们可以
innovation area where people can
existing members and committers can
现有成员和提交者可以以非常低的成本创建自己的项目
create their own projects with very low
overhead and I was on the James project
开销，我在詹姆斯项目中工作了很多年，有一个项目
for many years and there was project
management committee chair of James for
詹姆斯（James）的管理委员会主席已有数年的历史了。
a number of years Labs is available to
any committer they can subscribe to the
他们可以订阅实验室邮件列表的任何提交者，并且他们可以
labs mailing list and they can
tell us what their idea is and we'll
告诉我们他们的想法是什么，我们将为他们启动一个迷你项目，
spin up a mini project for them that has
all of the infrastructure of Apache
Apache的所有基础架构，然后他们可以进行实验
behind it and then they can experiment
in there and attempt to get other people
并尝试让其他人对他们的想法感兴趣，这可能是一个
interested in their idea it could be an
experiment that is is time boxed or that
有时间限制的实验或达到特定目标的实验，然后
they achieve a particular goal and then
it's over with or it can be something
结束了，或者可能是他们想要合作的地方，
where they they want to collaborate and
try things out and see if there's a
尝试一下，看看背后是否有临界质量，然后他们
critical mass behind it and then they
can attempt to become a an Apache
可以尝试用它成为一个Apache项目
project with it
it was created at a time before github
它是在github成为问题之前创建的，我认为其中的大多数
was a thing and I think most of the of
that activity is now supported on github
该活动现已在github上得到支持，因此我们对实验室的兴趣减少了
so we're seeing less interest in labs
but times change and the trend is maybe
但是时代在变化，趋势可能是趋势会反过来摆动
the trend will swing back the other way
and perhaps if you people are watching
也许如果您的人们正在观看此视频，他们认为这是一个很好的选择
this video and they think it's a good
idea they can subscribe to the labs list
他们可以订阅实验室列表并创建实验室
and come and create a lab
[Music]
[音乐]